Guide to the Time Inc. Corporate Administration Records 1853-1997 MS 3009-RG 5
New-York Historical Society
Time Inc. Corporate Administration Records
1853-1997
New-York Historical Society
Time, inc.
MS 3009-RG 5
20 Linear feet in 19 record cartons and 2 flat boxes
The General Files from the Corporate Administration Records include corporate-level records where the exact office of origination isn't known, or the files are from several people or offices at the corporate executive level, but were grouped together by Time Inc. at some point. Records include stock certificates, five-year plans, notary seals, patents, printing agreements, and organizational records from affiliates and subsidiaries.
Arrangement Note
The General Files are organized into nine series:
Series I.A. General: Stock
Series I.B. General: Contract, Corporate, and Corporate Secretary Legal Files
Series I.C. General: Dead Companies
Series I.D. General: Five-Year Plans
Series I.E. General: Notary Seals
Series I.F. General: Patents
Series I.G. General: Printing Agreements
Series I.H. General: Subsidiary Corporate Books
Series I.I. General: Time Warner Corporate Structure Books
Historical Note
The Corporate Administrative division of Time Inc. encompasses the positions of chairman of the Board of Directors, chairman of the executive committee, secretary, treasurer, chief executive officer, president, chief financial officer, executive vice president, group vice president, and vice president. Some of these positions are frequently held at the same time by the same person. Group vice presidents are usually the head of a division of Time Inc. such as the Books Group or Video Group, and the records for that position will be with that record group. The editor-in-chief is listed as part of the corporate group management, but their files are in the record group for corporate editorial.
Chairman of the Board
1980-1986 Ralph P. Davidson
1986-1990 J. Richard Munro
1990-1997 Reginald K. Brack
1997-2002 Don Logan
Chief Executive Officer
1969-1980 Andrew Heiskell
1980-1989 J. Richard Munro
1990-1994 Reginald K. Brack
1994-2002 Don Logan
President
1923-1929 Henry R. Luce / Briton Hadden (alternated as President and Treasurer)
1929-1938 Henry R. Luce
1939-1959 Roy E. Larsen
1960-1969 James A. Linen
1970-1980 James R. Shepley
1981-1986 J. Richard Munro
1986-1990 N. J. Nicholas, Jr.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers with the exception of restricted materials. Restricted materials may include privileged attorney correspondence and contracts and agreements. Materials created within the past 35 years also may be subject to restriction on a case-by-case basis. Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Unreformatted audiovisual and digital material in the collection is not accessible.
Related Archival Materials Note
This finding aid relates to just one record group of the Time Inc. Records. For information about the other record groups and for overall information about the archives, please see the Guide to the Time Inc. Records (MS 3009). The Henry Luce Papers (MS 3014) were acquired with the Time Inc. Records. The collection of books acquired with the records are cataloged as the Time Inc. Reference Library.
Scope and Contents Note
The General Files from the Corporate Administration Records include corporate-level records where the exact office of origination isn't known, or the files are from several people or offices at the corporate executive level, but were grouped together by Time Inc. at some point. Records include stock certificates, five-year plans, notary seals, patents, printing agreements, and organizational records from affiliates and subsidiaries.
Provenance
Gift of Time Inc. in 2015.
Accruals
Further additions to this finding aid are expected.
Stock certificates; Seals; Printing industry; Patents; Organization files; Corporations -- New York (State) -- New York.; Corporations -- History; Corporation records; Certificates of incorporation; Publishers and publishing -- New York (State) -- New York.; Time, inc. -- Archives; Time, inc. -- History
- Series I.A. General: Stock, 1929-1934, 1964; 222777; 5 Linear feet in 4 record cartons and 2 flat boxes
  Scope and Contents Note
  Stock includes canceled Time Inc. stock certificates, stock split ledgers listing the stockholder, account number, and shares owned; and stock books from which certificates were written.
  Arrangement Note
  Organized alphabetically by document format.
  - Stock Certificates: 1929-1933, 227829 (Offsite-box 2047)
  - Stock Certificates: 1931 June - 1933 June, 1931-1933; 222780 (Offsite-box 772)
  - Stock Certificates: 1933 June - 1933 September, 222779 (Offsite-box 773)
  - Stock Certificates: 1933 September - 1934 June and Undated, 1933-1934; 222778 (Offsite-box 774)
  - Stock Split Ledgers, 1964; 222797 (Offsite-box 1789)
  - Stock Books: Time Inc., 1929-1933 (Offsite-box 2832)
  - Stock Books: March of the Years, 1933 (Offsite-box 2832)
  - Stock Books: March of Time, 1934-1935 (Offsite-box 2832)
- Series I.B. General: Contract, Corporate, and Corporate Secretary Legal Files, 1853, 1875, 1888, 1898-1901, 1922-1965; 222743; 5 Linear feet in 5 record cartons
  Contract, Corporate, and Corporate Secretary Legal Files are similar to the subseries Dead Companies, but were not included on the lists found with the transfer of Dead Companies to the Time Inc. Archives. These are a mix of files from defunct companies and old business arrangements made by Time Inc. and include acquisition and sale agreements, articles of incorporation and dissolution, meeting minutes, correspondence, publishing contracts, and title searches. The files come from Arnold Carlson as Controller (or Comptroller), John "Jack" Harvey as Comptroller, Peter Sheppe as Director of Administrative Services (Comptroller department), and Dean Chamberlain (business manager Time-Life International and then Corporate Circulation.) There are notes showing that some records are from the "Contract file"; files sent to Ronnie Biehl for the "Corp file"; and files from the "Corp Sec [Corporate Secretary] Legal file cabinet." Additional and more complete publishing agreements are in the subseries Printing Agreements.
  Organized alphabetically.
  - Albuquerque Broadcasting [RESTRICTED], 1952-1957; 222776 (Offsite-box 612, Folder 1-7)
  - Aladdin and LTF [RESTRICTED], approximately 1957-1960; 222775 (Offsite-box 612, Folder 8-11)
  - Architectural Forum [RESTRICTED], 1941-1965; 222774 (Offsite-box 612-613)
    Includes records regarding Wilson H. Lee Company.
  - Barges-N. L. Wallace and C. L. Stillman [RESTRICTED], 1950-1963; 222773 (Offsite-box 613, Folder 4-6)
  - Blue Network Company [RESTRICTED], 1943-1948; 222772 (Offsite-box 613, Folder 7)
  - Chicago title searches, 1853, 1875, 1888, 1898-1901; 222771 (Offsite-box 613, Folder 8-9)
  - Compania Editora, T. L. I. [RESTRICTED], 1951-1965; 222770 (Offsite-box 613, Folder 10-14)
    Regarding a Time Life International publishing agreement in Cuba.
  - Consolidated Television & Radio Broadcasters, Inc. [RESTRICTED], 1956-1957; 222769 (Offsite-box 613-614)
  - Cuneo Press [RESTRICTED], 1929-1939; 222768 (Offsite-box 614, Folder 3-5)
    Includes records regarding publishing Architectural Forum and Fortune.
  - De Luxe Laboratories [RESTRICTED], 1946; 222767 (Offsite-box 614, Folder 6)
  - F-Miscellaneous [George A. Fuller Company] [RESTRICTED], 1956-1958; 222766 (Offsite-box 614, Folder 7)
  - Fulfillment Corporation of America [RESTRICTED], 1948-1956; 222765 (Offsite-box 614, Folder 8)
  - Hay, John I. Co. [John I. Hay Company] [RESTRICTED], 1941-1952; 222764 (Offsite-box 614, Folder 9)
  - Hennepin Paper Co. [RESTRICTED], 1945-1948; 222763 (Offsite-box 614, Folder 10-11)
  - Hillcrest Oil Company [RESTRICTED], 1957-1962; 222762 (Offsite-box 614, Folder 12-13)
  - Lebanon Television Station (La Compagnie Libanaise de Television) [RESTRICTED], 1961-1963; 222761 (Offsite-box 614, Folder 14)
  - Life's Picture History of World War II [RESTRICTED], 1950-1951; 222760 (Offsite-box 614, Folder 15)
  - Old Life - Purchase [RESTRICTED], 1936-1941; 222759 (Offsite-box 614, Folder 16)
    Contains purchase agreements of the Life humor magazine in order to obtain the rights to use the title "Life."
  - Literary Digest: Purchase [RESTRICTED], 1922-1938; 222758 (Offsite-box 614, Folder 17)
    Includes trademark transfers.
  - Lubin, Eisner, 1954-1955; 222757 (Offsite-box 614-615)
    Include records relating to Michigan Square Building and Printing Developments, Inc.
  - L Miscellaneous [Joe Louis Enterprises, Inc.] [RESTRICTED], 1948; 222756 (Offsite-box 615, Folder 2)
  - Maine Seaboard Paper Company [RESTRICTED], 1937-1952; 222755 (Offsite-box 615, Folder 3-13)
  - Michigan Square Building [RESTRICTED], 1941-1953; 222754 (Offsite-box 615, Folder 14-15)
  - N-Miscellaneous [National Broadcasting Company, Inc.] [RESTRICTED], 1954; 222753 (Offsite-box 615, Folder 16)
  - Pan American Capital Corporation [RESTRICTED], 1956-1961; 222752 (Offsite-box 615, Folder 17)
  - Publishers Printing Company [RESTRICTED], 1945-1948; 222751 (Offsite-box 615, Folder 18)
    Regarding the publishing of Architectural Forum.
  - Publishers Printing-Rogers Kellogg Corporation [RESTRICTED], 1930-1943; 222750 (Offsite-box 615, Folder 19)
    Regarding the publishing of Architectural Forum, and includes agreements with The Reader's Digest.
  - Readers Digest [RESTRICTED], 1941-1950; 222749 (Offsite-box 615, Folder 20)
  - Rogers & Manson Corporation [RESTRICTED], 1932-1959; 222748 (Offsite-box 615-616)
    Includes Architectural Forum 1932 Certificate of Incorporation.
  - Time-Fortune Corporation [RESTRICTED], 1932-1936; 222747 (Offsite-box 616, Folder 2)
  - Truman memoirs [RESTRICTED], 1953-1960; 222746 (Offsite-box 616, Folder 3-4)
    Records and agreements regarding purchasing the publishing rights to Harry S. Truman's memoirs.
  - Whitney, Courtney (General) [RESTRICTED], 1954-1963; 222745 (Offsite-box 616, Folder 5)
    Records and agreements regarding purchasing the publishing rights to his work about Douglas MacArthur.
  - Windsor, Duke of [RESTRICTED], 1947-1951; 222744 (Offsite-box 616, Folder 6)
    Includes copyright registrations from several countries for articles written by the Duke of Windsor.
- Series I.C. General: Dead Companies [RESTRICTED], 1946, 1950, 1957-1979; 222679; 3 Linear feet in 3 record cartons
  Dead Companies contains a group of materials accompanied by a transfer list naming the companies included. Records include acquisition and sale agreements, operation agreements, certificates of incorporation and dissolution, articles of merger, correspondence, and other corporate documents. The files come from Charles Bear as Secretary, Barry Zorthian as Vice President, John "Jack" Harvey as Comptroller, and Peter Sheppe as Director of Administrative Services (Comptroller department). There is cross-over of company names with the subseries Subsidiary Corporate Books.
  Organized alphabetically with lists of the companies at the front.
  - Lists, undated; 222742 (Offsite-box 606, Folder 1)
  - Aladdin / LTF, 1972; 222741 (Offsite-box 606, Folder 2)
  - American Health Corporation, 1973-1979; 222740 (Offsite-box 606, Folder 3)
  - Andre Deutsch Limited, 1969-1972; 222739 (Offsite-box 606, Folder 4)
  - Atari, Inc., 1975-1976; 222738 (Offsite-box 606, Folder 5)
  - British Telemeter Home Viewing, Limited, 1971-1972; 222737 (Offsite-box 606, Folder 6)
  - Cesar Civita, 1966; 222736 (Offsite-box 606, Folder 7)
  - Circle City Cable Corporation, 1966-1973; 222735 (Offsite-box 606, Folder 8)
  - Computer Television Inc., 1972-1975; 222734 (Offsite-box 606, Folder 9)
  - C T Land & Building Corp., 1962; 222733 (Offsite-box 606, Folder 10)
  - East Texas Cable Television Services, Inc., 1967-1972; 222732 (Offsite-box 606, Folder 11)
  - Family Publications Service, Inc., 1958, 1968-1974; 222731 (Offsite-box 606, Folder 12-13)
  - Haverhill's, Inc., 1971; 222730 (Offsite-box 606, Folder 14)
  - Heidelberg, S.A., 1970; 222729 (Offsite-box 606, Folder 15)
  - Itek Corporation, 1965; 222728 (Offsite-box 606, Folder 16)
  - Jasper Timber Company, 1960-1962, 1973; 222727 (Offsite-box 606, Folder 17-18)
  - J. W. Clement Company, 1962; 222726 (Offsite-box 606, Folder 19)
  - KOAK-CATV, Inc., 1967-1968; 222725 (Offsite-box 606, Folder 20-22)
  - Kelly Broadcasting, Inc., 1971; 222724 (Offsite-box 606, Folder 23)
  - KERO-TV / Transcontinent Television Corporation, 1963; 222723 (Offsite-box 606, Folder 24)
  - KFSD-FM / Lotus Communications Corp., 1973; 222722 (Offsite-box 606, Folder 25)
  - KLZ-AM and FM / Group One Broadcasting, Co., 1971-1972; 222721 (Offsite-box 607, Folder 1)
  - KOGO Broadcasting Corporation, 1961; 222720 (Offsite-box 607, Folder 2)
  - KOGO-AM, 1971; 222719 (Offsite-box 607, Folder 3)
  - Kokomo CATV, Inc., 1965-1970; 222718 (Offsite-box 607, Folder 4-5)
  - Lake Erie Cable Corporation, 1971-1972; 222717 (Offsite-box 607, Folder 6)
  - McGraw-Hill, 1970-1972; 222716 (Offsite-box 607, Folder 7-10)
  - Mid County Television Corporation, 1966; 222715 (Offsite-box 607, Folder 11)
  - Milwaukee Cablevision, Inc., 1971-1976; 222714 (Offsite-box 607, Folder 12)
  - Milwaukee Community TV, Inc., 1965, 1971; 222713 (Offsite-box 607, Folder 13)
  - Newcastle Broadcasting and TV Corporation, 1970; 222712 (Offsite-box 607, Folder 14)
  - Newton Timber Company, 1973; 222711 (Offsite-box 607, Folder 15)
  - Nutmeg State Communications Company, 1975; 222710 (Offsite-box 607, Folder 16)
  - Prindevincor Limited, 1975-1977; 222709 (Offsite-box 607, Folder 17)
  - Printing Developments, Inc., 1950; 222708 (Offsite-box 607, Folder 18)
  - Printing Developments International (France) S.A., 1963, 1977; 222707 (Offsite-box 607, Folder 19)
  - Printing Developments International (Panama) S.A., 1957, 1972; 222706 (Offsite-box 607, Folder 20)
  - Producciones Argentinas de Television S.A.C.I (Proartel), 1963-1973; 222705 (Offsite-box 607, Folder 21)
  - Proarkl, 1973; 222704 (Offsite-box 607, Folder 22)
  - The Quality School Plan Inc., 1964, 1971; 222703 (Offsite-box 607, Folder 23-24)
  - Rayburn Land Company, 1966; 222702 (Offsite-box 607, Folder 25)
  - Research Products, Inc., 1976; 222701 (Offsite-box 607, Folder 26)
  - San Augustine Timber Co., 1962-1973; 222700 (Offsite-box 607, Folder 27)
  - Silver Burdett Company, 1965; 222699 (Offsite-box 607, Folder 28)
  - St. Louis Cablevision Co., 1994; 222698 (Offsite-box 608, Folder 1)
  - T C Press Corporation, 1965, 1972; 222697 (Offsite-box 608, Folder 2)
  - T C Machinery Corporation, 1961-1963, 1973; 222696 (Offsite-box 608, Folder 3)
  - Teijin Ltd., 1973; 222695 (Offsite-box 608, Folder 4)
  - Tilon Incorporated, 1967, 1973; 222694 (Offsite-box 608, Folder 5)
  - Time Incorporated Societe Immobiliere, 1961; 222693 (Offsite-box 608, Folder 6)
  - Time-Life Broadcast, Inc., 1964, 1974; 222692 (Offsite-box 608, Folder 7)
  - Time-Life Cable TV of Michigan, Inc., 1971-1974; 222691 (Offsite-box 608, Folder 8)
  - Time-Life/Columbia Cable TV, Inc., 1975; 222690 (Offsite-box 608, Folder 9)
  - Time-Life International Inc., 1946, 1972; 222689 (Offsite-box 608, Folder 10)
  - Time-Life Newspapers, Inc., 1971; 222688 (Offsite-box 608, Folder 11)
  - Time Tele-Marketing, Inc., 1973-1976; 222687 (Offsite-box 608, Folder 12)
  - Time-Texas, Inc., 1973; 222686 (Offsite-box 608, Folder 13)
  - TLB Peru Inc., 1963; 222685 (Offsite-box 608, Folder 14)
  - TV-Globo / Time-Life Brasil, Inc., 1962-1972; 222684 (Offsite-box 608, Folder 15-17)
  - WFBM, 1971-1972; 222683 (Offsite-box 608, Folder 18)
  - Windrose - Dumont - Time, 1961-1966; 222682 (Offsite-box 608, Folder 19)
  - Wisconsin Community TV, Inc., 1971; 222681 (Offsite-box 608, Folder 20)
  - WOOD Broadcasting Inc., 1971; 222680 (Offsite-box 608, Folder 21)
- Series I.D. General: Five-Year Plans, 1971; 222678; 1 Linear feet in 1 record carton (Offsite-box 864, Folder 1-11)
  Organized alphabetically with the overview plan at the front.
  Contains Five-Year Plans sent to a small group of corporate officers. Includes an overview and outlines of the strategic plans and plans for Books and Arts Associates, Fortune, Printing Developments Division, Real Estate Division, Selling Areas Marketing Plan (SAMI), Sports Illustrated, Time, Time-Life Films, Time-Life Records (music albums), and Time-life Video. Two copies originally belonged to Louis Banks, who was either Fortune's managing editor or the overall editorial director in 1971. It is not clear who ultimately collected and retained these plans.
- Series I.E. General: Notary Seals, undated; 222677; 1 Linear feet in 1 record carton (Offsite-box 619)
  Notary Seals are a collection of seals from defunct Time Inc. affiliates and subsidiaries. The seals were used for embossing. There is cross-over of names with Dead Companies.
  In original order.
- Series I.F. General: Patents, 1935-1964; 222676; 1 Linear feet in 1 record carton (Offsite-box 620)
  In original arrangement of individual alphabetical files followed by general files.
  Patents contains records of patents owned by Time Inc. and include patent applications and transfer of patent ownership. These patents were found housed together. Inventions covered include the mailing envelope, ink composition, casein techniques, paper coating, printing machine components and mechanisms, and chrome plating.
- Series I.G. General: Printing Agreements, 1939-1948; 222675; 1 Linear feet in 1 record carton (Offsite-box 617)
  Organized chronologically.
  Printing Agreements contains bound agreements that detail the work to be done, the term, plant facilities, and equipment to be used. These agreements were found housed together. The majority of agreements relate to printing Life with one Fortune printing agreement from 1948. The printers are The Cuneo Press or R. R. Donnelley & Sons Company. Some covers are stamped with "Contract file." Similar, but not as complete, agreements are in the subseries Contract, Corporate, and Corporate Secretary Legal Files.
- Series I.H. General: Subsidiary Corporate Books, 1949-1974; 222658; 6 Linear feet in 6 record cartons
  Subsidiary Corporate Books include bound volumes of business records of companies that were acquired by Time Inc. such as printers, paper mills, and radio or television stations. These volumes were housed together. Records include articles of incorporation, by-laws, and meeting minutes. There is cross-over of names with the subseries Dead Companies.
  - Alva Studios, Inc., 1949-1961; 222674 (Offsite-box 608, Folder 22-23)
  - Cascade Television Cable Company, 1965-1971; 222673 (Offsite-box 608, Folder 24)
  - East Texas Pulp and Paper Company, 1953-1971; 222672 (Offsite-box 609, Folder 1-4)
  - Family Publications Service, Inc., 1963-1971; 222671 (Offsite-box 609, Folder 5-8)
  - Huntington Cable Television, Inc., 1966-1972; 222670 (Offsite-box 609, Folder 9)
  - Jasper Timber Company, 1960-1973; 222669 (Offsite-box 610, Folder 1)
  - Lake Erie Cable Corporation, 1966-1971; 222668 (Offsite-box 610, Folder 2)
  - Mador Communications Corp., 1958-1971; 222667 (Offsite-box 610, Folder 3)
  - Rayburn Country Improvement Association, 1965-1970; 222666 (Offsite-box 610, Folder 4)
  - Rayburn Land Company / Rayburn Lodge and Marina Company / Rayburn Village Water Company, 1965; 222665 (Offsite-box 610, Folder 5)
  - St. Francisville Paper Company, 1957-1959; 222664 (Offsite-box 610-611)
  - St. Louis Cabletelevision, 1967-1971; 222663 (Offsite-box 611, Folder 2)
  - The Southwestern Cable Company, 1964-1972; 222662 (Offsite-box 611, Folder 3)
  - Tilon Incorporated, 1967-1973; 222661 (Offsite-box 611, Folder 4)
  - Time-Life/Columbia Cable TV Inc., 1970-1974; 222660 (Offsite-box 611, Folder 5)
  - Twin State Broadcasting, Inc., 1959; 222659 (Offsite-box 611, Folder 6)
- Series I.I. General: Time Warner Corporate Structure Books, 1994-1997; 222657; 1 Linear feet in 1 record carton (Offsite-box 864, Folder 12-15)
  Time Warner Corporate Structure Books contain information assembled by the Corporate Tax Department. Information includes lists of mergers, new subsidiaries, investments, and sales; lists of Time Warner and affiliated entities; lists of division names and trade names; and corporate structure trees of each entity, division, or subsidiary. Changes made since the last book are listed at the front.